# Mezekr Weldu

Full-stack web developer



mezekr.weldu@tutamail.com 📞 +49 (0)17644546546 🛖 Frankfurt (Main), Germany 🕮 Portfolio 📺 LinkedIn









# Summary

Full-stack web developer with experience in responsive websites, web applications, and mobile apps using React Native, through recent completion of CareerFoundry's 900+ hour, project-based full-stack web development certification program. Has 2+ years of software development experience in data processing and machine learning. Seeks an opportunity in full-stack web development to tackle complex challenges, bring innovative ideas to life, and deliver customized solutions that meet client needs.

### **Skills & Tools**

#### **Frontend**

- HTML, CSS, JavaScript, TypeScript
- Frameworks & Libraries: React, Angular, Redux, AJAX, jQuery, Material, SASS/SCSS, Tailwind CSS, **Bootstrap**
- Mobile App: React Native, Expo, PWA
- Testing: TDD & BDD, Jest, Cucumber, Puppeteer
- UX/UI Design: User Stories, User Flow, Wireframes

#### **Backend**

- Node.js & Express, Vite, Webpack, Npm
- RESTful API, JSON, Insomnia / Postman
- AWS Lambda, Firebase, Appwrite, Render, Netlify
- Databases: SQL, PostgreSQL, MySQL, MongoDB
- DevOps: Docker, CI/CD

#### Data processing and visualization

· Python, Numpy, matplotlip, plotly, Scipy, Libros, Jupyter Notebook

#### **Devtools**

• Git, GitHub, GitLab, VScode, WSL, Ubuntu

# **Education & Certificates**

#### **Certificate in Full Stack Web Development**

CareerFoundry (Remote)

12.2023 - 06.2024

- 900+ hours of immersive, project-based training that prioritizes best practices, guided by an industry-leading tutor and mentor.
- Focused on JavaScript, Typescript, HTML, CSS and frameworks/libraries including React, Angular, Nodejs, Express, MongoDB and React Native for mobile app development.
- Completed 6+ hands-on projects on the web technologies stack, resulting in the development of interactive and responsive web apps and implementing appealing to UX/UI.

## M.S. in Applied Computer Science

TU Bergakademie Freiberg

10.2019 - 09.2022

**B.S.** in Computer Engineering

09.2008 -

Eritrean Institute of Technology, Mai-Nefhi | 07.2013

## Language

- German, fluent written and spoken (C1)
- · English, fluent written and spoken

# **Selected Web Development Projects**

## MeziFlix-app (Back-end)

01.2024 - 02.2024

Server-side app business logic for storing and managing movies & users

- Provides a RESTful API developed with Node.js, Express, MongoDB and integrates JWT and Passport for authentication
- Conducted comprehensive API tests with Insomnia
- Tech-Stack: JavaScript, Nodejs, Express, MongoDB Atlas, mongosh, REST-API, JSON Insomnia, Git, GitHub, Docker API Code

## MeziFlix-client (Front-end)

02.2024 - 03.2024

Movies Hub app that enables users to create an account, access movie information, add/remove movies to favorites, and edit/delete their

- React responsive single page application (frontend client to Meziflix backend app)
- Developed using React and styled using CSS, Bootstrap and SASS
- **Tech-Stack**: HTML, CSS, JavaScript, React, Bootstrap, Material, Git, GitHub, REST-API, Docker

MeziFlix-client

#### **Mezimeet App**

03.2023 - 04.2024

PWA lets users discover events in cities worldwide, displaying event details and filtering by city or number...

- Developed using TDD methodology, covering unit, integration, and end-to-end testing
- Implemented with AWS Lambda Serverless, React, and fetches upcoming events from the Google Calendar API
- Tech-Stack: JavaScript, React, CSS, SASS, Jest , Puppeteer, Cucumber, Recharts

Mezimeet

Code

# **Professional Experience**

# **Software Developer**

FERCHAU GmbH (Pulsotronic GmbH & Co.)

03.2023 - 07.2024

- Implemented a software module for data pre-processing and statistical analysis, resulting in more accurate frequency analysis.
- Tech-Stack: Python, Pandas, Scipy, Librosa, Git, Gitlab, Jupyter Notebook, Plotly

#### Software developer in the research project DiP-IT

TU Bergakademie Freiberg

12.2020 - 06.2022

- Streamlined data retrieval by engineering a Python package to fetch open source repository data from GitHub using RestAPI, resulting in efficient data storage for analysis.
- Optimized data quality by conducting thorough data cleaning, processing, and anomaly detection, resulting in improved decisionmaking and enhanced business outcomes.
- · Created an algorithm to address the GitHub RestAPI rate limit, improving data handling and fetching time.
- Tech-Stack: Python, Pandas, Git, GitHub, GitHub REST-API, Jupyter Notebook